ABDOU-BASSITOU KOUKOUWE

Security Management | Operational security coordinator



SUMMARY

Operational security coordinator with 5 years experience. Acting as primary contact with other stakeholders on operational security related concerns. Working on user accounts reporting, remediation, and follow-up security relay between security and different user service management teams. Working effectively with cross-functional teams to achieve security objectives.

EDUCATION

Oxford Home Study Center OHSC

Diploma in Cyber security: 2024 Introduction to Cyber security, Cyber security tools and techniques, developing policies and risk mitigation plan

Université de Lomé

Bachelor's Degree of Arts and Language 2013-2016: Focus on German studies, English and French.

SKILLS

- Incident management (ServiceNow)
- Request management (ServiceNow)
- SecOps SIR
- Active Directory
- Change Advisory Board (CAB)
- UserCube (Reporting)
- Microsoft 365 products
- Cybersecurity
- Coordination with different groups
- Strong organizational and time management skills
- Detail-oriented
- · Multiple tasks handling.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified in Cybersecurity, by ISC2
- Cybersecurity Awareness Professional Certification, by Certiprof;
- IBM IT Support Specialization, by Coursera
- Microsoft Certified: Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals (SC-900) and Azure Fundamentals: (AZ-900)
- International English Language Test Certificate: C1
- ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management by Axelos certified People Cert.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Security Management - Internal control and Operational Security Coordinator

Tata Consultancy Services Limited (TCS Hungary)| June 2021 - Present

- Leading team of 3 co-workers: Create and keep up-to-date documentation, and train co-workers
- ·Manage, escalate and Coordinate security-alerts until resolution using ServiceNow SecOps SIR.
- ·Follow-up security relay between security and different user service management teams
- Participate to weekly security meeting with Security Operation Center (SOC) for ongoing security alerts.
- Audit and remediate user accounts: to make users compliant with security policy and to free up unused licenses.
- Manage approximately 55 sensible access requests daily

End User Support - Security management associate

Tata Consultancy Services Limited (TCS Hungary)| June 2021 - Present

- Acted as resolution team: Track and monitor security-related tickets created by Security Operation Center (Approximately 15 tickets per week)
- Participated in weekly security reports for security concerns with SOC team.
- Managed sensible access requests, approximately 50 requests daily
- Guided and advised End-Users Over phone, email, and chat
- Created monthly Reports for different clients' subbranches and performed remediation
- Contributed to creation of documentation.